Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/mayurbhorkar (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Machine Learning

Angular

Microsoft Azure

Languages

English

Marathi

Hindi

Certifications

[PCEP-30-01] PCEP – Certified Entry-Level Python Programmer

Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist (MCTS)

Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate

IELTS General Training Overall Band Scores: 7.5

Mayur Bhorkar

Principal Software Developer at Hexagon | MSc Data Science & Al, University of London

London, England, United Kingdom

Summary

Full stack software developer having 13+ years of experience with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in Asp.net, .net core, MVC, C#, Web API, Microsoft Azure, Docker, Kubernetes, AKS, WCF, Web Services, MS-SQL, Oracle, Angular 12+, NodeJS, Angular JS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript, jQuery, MongoDB, MEAN Stack, Mobile development using IONIC, MEIN Stack, Jasmine Framework, Python, Machine Learning, XSLT, JSON, XML, VSTS, CI-CD, GIT, Github, Bitbucket, JIRA, Confluence, Agile, SCRUM, VB.NET, SSRS & Crystal Reports etc. . Strong consulting professional with a Masters of Science (MSc) focused in Data Science and AI from University of London, UK.

Experience

Hexagon Asset Lifecycle Intelligence Principal Software Developer May 2022 - Present (3 years 2 months) London, England, United Kingdom

Capgemini

4 years 9 months

Senior Consultant

February 2019 - May 2022 (3 years 4 months)

London, Greater London, United Kingdom

Worked as a Software Developer with our client VOLKSWAGEN FINANCIAL SERVICES (VWFS), Milton Keynes ,UK

Senior Consultant

September 2017 - February 2019 (1 year 6 months)

Mumbai Area, India

Role and Responsibilities:

- * Designing Web UI using Angular JS, Angular 4, Typescript, HTML, CSS, BootStrap.
- * Developing Web API using MVC framework, C#, LINQ, Entity framework, Repository pattern, MS SQL

Server.

- * Designing Mobile UI using IONIC 3, Angular 4, Typescript, HTML, CSS.
- * Developing Mobile API using NodeJS & ExpressJS, MongoDB.
- * Developed and demonstrated POC for Mobile App using MEIN Stack Framework to Sr. Managers & Delivery heads.
- * Received Golden Badge Certificate for Employee of the 1st Quarter 2018 (JAN-MAR) from RMG.
- * Onsite Visit to Romania for requirement gathering and K.T with client.
- * Requirement gathering and interaction with clients & client Support.
- * Analysis of the application and divide task to team member.
- * Maintain various application source code repositories on BitBucket.
- * Maintain Daily task and documents on JIRA & Confluence.
- * Experience of working in SCRUM-Agile Methodology.
- * Monitor & Maintain Application resources on Microsoft Azure.
- * Application Deployment on Non Production Environments using Continuous Integration and Delivery

(CI-CD) using VSTS

Volkswagen Financial Services (UK)
Web Developer
February 2019 - May 2022 (3 years 4 months)
Milton Keynes, England, United Kingdom

Worked as a Software Developer with VWFS UK on contract basis with Capgemini

WCA World Software Engineer February 2015 - July 2017 (2 years 6 months) Mumbai Area, India

Role and Responsibilities:

- * Designing UI & Developing Web APIs using MVC framework, C#, LINQ, Entity framework, Repository pattern, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, SQL Store Procedures and Views.
- * Developing Electronic Messages using XSLT and sending it to the airlines via FTP, SMTP etc. [As per IATA

specific format].

- * Reading and processing Electronic Messages [IATA format] received from airlines.
- * Application Deployment on UAT & LIVE Environment.
- * Requirement gathering and interaction with clients & client Support.
- * Designing Functional & Technical Documents for Change Request.

Kale Logistics Solutions

3 years 9 months

Senior Programmer Analyst
May 2013 - January 2015 (1 year 9 months)

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

Programmer Analyst

January 2012 - May 2013 (1 year 5 months)

Mumbai Area, India

Role and Responsibilities:

Designing & Developing Windows & Web Applications using ASP.net, C#, VB.net, Web Services, HTML,

CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, SSRS & CRSYTAL REPORTS, SQL Store Procedures, Functions, Views.

- # Windows and Web Application Deployment on UAT & LIVE Environment.
- # Requirement gathering & interaction with Clients, understanding and developing Clients CR, User

Training on Client Side, Client Support.

- # Involved in the Core development team, worked on Dot Net 4.0 with SQL Server 2008 R2.
- # Visited client site for product "Go-LIVE" for the period of one month at Mumbai International Airport as

well as at Cochin International Airport, thus have an extensive experience in Client handling and

ensuring smooth delivery on committed deadlines.

Programmer Analyst Trainee

May 2011 - December 2011 (8 months)

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

Education

University of London

Master of Science - MS, Data Science & Artificial Intelligence · (October 2020 - March 2023)

The KET's V. G. Vaze College of Arts, Science & Commerce (Autonomous)

Bachelor of Science (BSc), Information Technology · (2008 - 2011)

Datta Meghe College of Engineering CIDCO Sector III Airoli Navi Mumbai 400 708

Diploma, Information Technology · (2005 - 2008)

New English School SSC · (1995 - 2005)